（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
Even within that brilliant history,
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
Despite being relatively unknown
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
and lacking a game record,
にもかかわらず—
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
幻のシックスマンがいた と
A phantom sixth man.
Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Now!
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
Your light is too dim.
（青峰(あおみね)）オマエの光は… 淡すぎる
（青峰）
もう バスケの何が楽しいんだよ
What's fun about basketball anymore?
（黒子(くろこ)）はあ はあ
Tetsu...
（青峰）テツ
（黒子）ん？
（青峰）
オレに勝てるのは オレだけだ
The only one who can beat me is me.
（火神(かがみ)）“強くなりすぎて
つまんなくなった”？
It's boring because you're too strong?
"The only one who can beat me is me"?
“オレに勝てるのは オレだけ”？
The Generation of Miracles is full of those guys!
“キセキの世代”は
そんなんばっかか！
Let's go beat him and wake him up!
さくっと勝って
目ぇ覚ましてやらぁ
Sorry...
（今吉(いまよし)）すまんのー
ウチらは まぁ… 前座や
I guess you could call us the opening act.
You'll know once Aomine gets here.
青峰が来たら 分かるわ
ワシらなんて
かわいーもんやで ホンマ
We're cute little kids compared to him.
Episode 16
Let's Go
Touou
Seirin
（若松(わかまつ)）ふんっ おらぁ！
（水戸部(みとべ)）くっ！
っしゃ コラ どっせぇーい！
All right, take this!
（観客１）すげえパス！
What an amazing pass!
毎度 どんな かけ声やねん
What are you going to say this time?
I'll stop you.
（伊月(いづき)）止める！
（伊月）なっ…
ダブルクラッチ！？
A double clutch?
When you heard Aomine would be late,
（今吉）おおかた
青峰が遅れるて聞いて—
できるだけ点差つけようと
思てたんちゃう？
I bet you thought you could open
up a big lead before he showed up.
Sorry, I guess I misspoke.
まあ スマン
こっちの言い方が悪かったわ
（伊月）な…？
（今吉）“前座”言うても—
We're only an opening act compared to Aomine.
“青峰と比べて”っちゅー話や
We're probably stronger than you.
君らよりは強いで たぶん
Touou
Seirin
They're strong!
（リコ）強い！
ここまでとはね…
I didn't think they'd be this strong.
If they're this good without Aomine, we're screwed.
これでまだ 青峰君がいないなんて
まいっちゃうわ
（降旗(ふりはた)）うお！ やっぱり
（河原(かわはら)）なんだよ？ 降旗
Really?
What is it, Furihata?
Touou's preliminary tournament scores:
予選トーナメントの
桐皇のスコア
108 to 91, 151 to 72, 131 to 81.
（河原）108 対 91
151 対 72
131 対 81…！
That's amazing. They're all 100 point games.
スゲェ 全部100点ゲーム！？
Yeah, they're the opposite of Seiho.
（リコ）そ つまり正邦(せいほう)とは
真逆のチーム
An offensive team.
超攻撃型よ
Sorry!
（桜井(さくらい)）すいません！
Damn it, I can't block him!
（日向(ひゅうが)）くっそー
ブロックしづれー！
跳んだと同時に 放ってきやがる！
He's shooting while jumping!
つーか 謝るぐれーなら打つな！
And if you're going to apologize,
don't shoot in the first place!
These guys...
（日向）しかも こいつら…
Oh, sorry!
ああっ すいません！
（諏佐(すさ)）くぅっ
（火神）こいつら…
These guys...
Their care for their teammates is minimal,
味方のケアは最小限で—
and there's no coordination at all.
譲り合うような連係は
まったくしねえ
Their offense and defense is all one-on-one.
オフェンスもディフェンスも
とにかく１対１
自分でボールを取りに行って
自分で決める…
You get the ball yourself and score yourself.
They keep coming at us with individual skill!
個人技で ひたすら
ガンガンきやがる！
へっ なるほどね
I see.
I expected some of this, but that's your style.
ある程度 予想してたけど
やっぱり そういうスタイルっスか
That's right.
せや ウチのチームは
全国から 選手を集めとる
Our team gathered athletes from all across the country.
The more skilled a player is, the stronger his sense of self.
１人１人が実力ある分
我が強く クセもある
We've been trying all sorts of things in the last few years though.
ここ数年
いろいろ試したんやけどな—
お手々つないで 仲良うやるより
このやり方が 一番しっくりくるわ
More than holding hands and playing nice, this way works best.
We're both offensive teams.
お互い 同じ攻撃型チーム
This game should be interesting.
面白くなりそうや
面白いかどうかは ともかく—
I don't know how interesting it will be.
同じってのは どうかな？
I'm not even sure we're the same type.
Our style is complete team play.
ウチのスタイルは
あくまで 全員一丸の攻撃なんで
Hey!
（若松）オラ！
Forget one-on-ones.
１対１の勝負はともかく…
ふっ！
I don't plan on losing this game.
試合にまで 負ける気はねーぞ
Tell your captain, you apologetic mushroom.
主将にもそう言っとけ 謝りキノコ
What? Sorry!
ええ！？ すいません！
I didn't say anything!
（桜井）ボク何も言ってないのに！
ていうか“謝りキノコ”って…
And what's an apologetic mushroom?
（今吉）ははは 何言うたか
聞こえんかったけど—
I didn't hear what you said, but I understood something...
なんか伝わったわ
from your play!
プレーでな！
（観客１）うお！
またロングパス！？
Another long pass?
They're fast! Isn't No. 6 a center?
（観客２）速(はえ)ぇ！ つか
先頭の６番 センターだろぉ！？
Between our individual style and your coordinated style,
個人技重視の
ウチのスタイルと—
連係重視の そっちのスタイル—
let's see whose is better.
どっちが上か 決めよか
I called it complete team play.
さっき全員一丸とは言ったけど
よく 忘れられるヤツが
いるんっスよ
Most people forget.
（若松）うお 速っ！
He's fast!
No, he's not!
（若松）…いわけじゃねえ！？
動き出しが早かったのか…
He started fast, but...
つか どっから湧いた
テメェ コラァ！
Where did this guy come from anyway?
He's too low!
でも 低ーい！
（火神）ったく
慣れねーことすっからだ アホ！
Don't try things you're not used to, you idiot!
（若松）たっか！
So high!
Too high! He's way too high!
（若松）…すぎだろ バカ！
跳びすぎっつーか…
ナニ人だ オマエ コラァ〜！
What nationality are you?
Nice, Kagami! You too, Kuroko.
（伊月）ナイス 火神！—
と 黒子！
なんだ あのショボいジャンプ
What was that sad jump?
If you can't get it, don't jump!
取れねーなら 跳ぶな！
（黒子）取れました
（火神）ウソつけ！
I got it.
Liar!
This isn't like you anyway.
そもそも らしくねーぞ
This isn't overlapping with your middle school experience, is it?
もしかして
オマエのいた中学と—
オーバーラップしてんじゃ
ねーだろな？
We're playing against Touou right now.
今の相手は桐皇学園だぞ！
寝てんのか！
Are you asleep?
But I got it.
（黒子）でも 取れました
（火神）ウソつけっ！
Liar!
（若松）クソが！
Those little shits have really done it now!
（若松）やってくれんじゃねーか！
（桜井）うわぁ…
Well, but...
（今吉）けどま… 聞いてた通りや
It's just like she said.
Oh?
（黄瀬(きせ)）ありゃ まーた遅刻っスわ
I'm late again, and they're losing again.
しかもまた 負けてるし… ん？
Midorimacchi?
（黄瀬）緑間(みどりま)っち
（緑間）ん？
Kise?
（緑間）黄瀬っ！
なぜ 気付いたのだよ？
How did you know it was me?
（黄瀬）アホスか
サングラスって…
Are you stupid?
Those sunglasses are embarrassing.
恥ずかしいから
ソッコー外してほしいっス！
Please take them off.
What?
なにぃ！？
What's with the box?
しかも 何スか？ その箱
It's today's lucky item, of course.
（緑間）今日のラッキーアイテムに
決まっているのだよ
あれスか？ 見たくないとか
周りには言ったけど—
Is that it?
You told everyone you didn't want to see the game, but you came anyway?
結局 来ちゃった みたいな？
Don't say that!
（緑間）テキトーなことを言うな！
近くを通っただけなのだよ！
I just happened to be in the area!
Isn't your house on the other end of town?
（黄瀬）家 真逆じゃないスか
（緑間）う…
So, how's the game?
（黄瀬）で どースか？ 試合は
Nothing special.
（緑間）どうもこうもない
話にならないのだよ
This is ridiculous.
Aomine doesn't seem to be here,
青峰がいないようだが それでも
ついていくのでやっとだ
but they can barely keep up.
Aominecchi's not here?
青峰っち いないんスか？
Well, those two just scored. They're just getting started.
まあ 今 あの２人が
決めたじゃないスか
これからっスよ
Have you forgotten, Kise?
忘れたのか 黄瀬
Touou has Momoi as well.
桐皇には 桃井(ももい)もいるのだよ
She is not just a manager.
（緑間）あいつは
ただのマネージャーではないだろう
During middle school, she helped us many times.
中学時代 何度も助けられたのだよ
つまり 逆に 敵になると
この上なく やっかいだ
In other words, if she is your opponent, she becomes exceptionally hard to deal with.
Momocchi, huh?
（黄瀬）桃っちか… そーいや
青峰っちと幼なじみだったっスね
She's known Aominecchi since they were little, hasn't she?
って… ん？
Oh yeah, wasn't she in love Kurokocchi?
あの子 確か 黒子っちのこと
好きじゃなかったスか？
What if she can't play seriously against him?
むしろ 本気なんて
出せねーんじゃ…
Is that right?
そうだったのか？
はあ！？
気付いてなかったんスか？
What?! You didn't know?!
バレバレっつーか
むしろ 毎日—
It was obvious! She was all over him every day!
アタックしまくり
だったじゃないスか！
（さつき）テツくーん！
はい タオルとスポドリ
Tetsu, here's a towel and a sports drink!
Tetsu, let's walk home together.
テツくーん 一緒に帰ろー
Tetsu!
テツくーん
テーツくん
If you didn't know after seeing that, you must be a monkey!
あれ見て 気付かないとか
サルっスか！
What? What do you mean, a monkey?!
なにぃ！
サルとは何だ サルとは！
まあいい
だったら なおさらなのだよ
Well, if that's the case, it's all the more true then.
黒子が 試合で手を抜かれることを
望むはずがないのだよ
She would never wish for Kuroko to slack off in a game.
Her role may be different,
そもそも 形は違えど
あいつのバスケに対する姿勢は—
but her attitude towards basketball
is no different from an athlete's.
選手と遜色はない
試合で わざと負けるような
そんなタマではないだろう
She would never intentionally lose a basketball game.
So that's your ex-girlfriend everyone's been talking about.
オマエの元カノ よく見りゃ
フツーにかわいいじゃん
She's cute.
Is that so?
そうですか？
Hey! There's something annoying about the way you said that.
（火神）おい なんか
ウゼェんだけど その言い方
Well, you're right.
（黒子）まあ そうですね
What?
As long as she's not playing a game.
（黒子）試合じゃなければ
（火神）ん…？
I can see how they defeated a couple of kings.
（原澤(はらさわ)）さすが 王者を
撃破しただけは ありますねー
Coach, should we take a time out?
（さつき）監督 一度
タイムアウト取りますか？
No, it's fine.
They're still making corrections after observing the real thing.
あいつらは まだ 実物見て
少し修正してるだけですよ
Momoi, did you already hand those out?
それに 桃井さんのアレは
もう渡してありますよね？
Yes. They...
はい もう全部…
みんな 知ってます
already know everything.
（観客）おおー スティール！
A steal!
（火神）このヤロー
ずいぶん深く守ってんな
These bastards are playing off us.
外は捨てて とにかく
抜かせねーつもりか…
They're abandoning the outside so we can't get through.
（火神）ふんっ 甘(あめ)えよ！
You're naive!
A three? No...
スリー！？ いや…
That's...
（黄瀬）あれは…
（緑間）１人アリウープ！
A one man alley oop!
I know. I thought you might try that.
（さつき）知ってますよー
そう来ると思ってたから
（さつき）単純なんだから
ホント 男の子って
Boys really are so simple.
Those movements just now...
（火神）今の動き…
初めての対応じゃねえ！
It's like they've faced this before!
And they know about Kagami's low outside shooting precentage.
（日向）しかも 火神の
外の確率の低さもバレてる
In other words...
つまり…
We must have been studied
（リコ）研究されてるわね
恐らくあの子に
by that girl.
桃井の正体は
情報収集のスペシャリスト—
Momoi is an information gathering specialist.
She's an intelligence agent.
いわば 諜報部員ってわけね
Mitobe-senpai!
（降旗）水戸部先輩！
（福田(ふくだ)）行けー！
Go!
（さつき）フフッ
水戸部凛之助(りんのすけ)さん
Mitobe Rinnosuke.
あまり 博打は打たない職人気質(かたぎ)
相手が自分より大きい場合は…
A hard worker who doesn't take risks.
When his opponent is taller than him...
It's a hook shot!
（若松）フックシュートだろ！
知ってるっつんだ コラァ！
I already know!
They know!
（伊月）読まれてる！
This isn't good, is it?
（河原）まずくないすか？
何か 手を打たないと…
We have to do something.
There's no need!
必要ないわ！
このまま行くわよ
We'll keep playing like this!
What?
（小金井(こがねい)）え？
No matter how accurate their information, it's from the past.
（リコ）いくら 正確な情報を
持っていたとしても—
それは過去のもの
Humans grow.
人間は成長するのよ
Don't act like you understand when you don't even realize that!
そんな常識も知らないで
知ったかぶってんじゃないわよ！
Hyuga Junpei.
（さつき）日向順平(じゅんぺい)さん
決して スピードは速くない選手
Not a particularly fast player.
Goes for threes after breaking free from his man with screens and cuts instead of charging in.
だから 中には切り込まず—
スクリーンやカットで マークを
外してからスリーを狙う… けど…
However...
（伊月）よしっ かかった！
All right! They got him.
Hyuga's a pure shooter.
日向は ピュアシューターだ
けど 近年のバスケで—
But in modern basketball, a player who can only shoot from the outside isn't good enough.
外しか打てない選手では
勝負にならない
That's why he's been practicing to improve his dribbling skills since the Shutoku game.
だから 秀徳(しゅうとく)戦のあと
ひたすら練習して—
ドリブルスキルを 向上させたんだ
（日向）でぇぃっ
He's still not fast, and not only is it a new pattern,
（火神）まだ お世辞にも速いとは
言えねーが 初めてのパターン
but all he has shot so far today have been straight forward threes.
しかも 今日のプレーは
ノーフェイクのスリーのみ
They think I'm going to shoot.
相手の頭には
シュートしかない 抜ける！
I can make it!
I know.
知ってますよー
そうなると思ってたから
I thought you might try that.
Wha—
They haven't seen this pattern before!
（伊月）
初めて見せるパターンだぞ！
They shouldn't have this data!
そんなデータは ないはずなのに！
Normally, when confronted with a play missing from their data,
データにない手で来た場合
普通なら対応できない
a person cannot handle it.
だが 桃井は
集めたデータを分析し—
However, Momoi analyzes the data she collects and even reads how her opponents will grow.
その後 相手が
どう成長するかまで読んでくる！
Their height, weight, strengths, weaknesses, personality, habits...
（さつき）その人の身長･体重
長所･短所･性格･クセ—
全部集めて分析･解析
そして絞り込み
I gather all of it and analyze, interpret, and narrow the results.
The last piece of the puzzle is
最後の秘訣は…
女のカンよ
a woman's intuition.
（伊月）一度戻せ 日向！
（日向）えぃっ
Bring it back, Hyuga!
Izuki Shun.
（さつき）伊月 俊(しゅん)さん
Possesses exceptional spatial awareness from his "eagle eye."
桁違いの空間認識能力
イーグルアイの持ち主
It's no use.
（伊月）ダメだ どのパターンでも
読まれてる…
They know everything we'll do.
We can't break through!
攻めきれない！
But because he sees so much,
（さつき）でも
見え過ぎるからこそ—
he sometimes becomes unable to act.
時に 消極的になる
（伊月）えぇぃ… く…
Five more seconds and it's a turnover!
（観客）残り５秒でファウルだ！
（リコ）フン 甘いぞ小娘！
You're naive, girl.
（日向）うっ えぇぃ
さっきと同じじゃ抜けねーぞ
If it's the same as before, they won't get through!
It's okay.
大丈夫
彼は次 何するか分からない！
They don't know what's coming next.
（桜井）スクリーン！
いつの間に？
When did they set up that screen?
Not even with a woman's intuition.
たとえ 女のカンでもね！
（火神）オラー！
Touou
Seirin
っしゃー ナイス火神！
All right, nice, Kagami!
Good work as usual, Kuroko!
さすが
いい仕事するぜ 黒子！
（さつき）もー
相変わらず読めないなー
Sheesh! I can never read him.
Damn, this isn't going to be easy.
ちぇー やっぱ
一筋縄ではいかないもんですね
It's all right.
大丈夫ですよー
こうなるとも 思ってましたから
I thought this might happen.
（さつき）けど…
だから テツ君って好き！
But that's why I love Tetsu!
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Touou
Seirin
A four point difference.
４点差か… まあ こんなもんやろ
Well, it figures.
With Momoi's data, we can still beat them.
つーか 桃井のデータだけで
十分勝てんぜ あれなら
青峰来ても 必要ねーよ！
We don't need Aomine!
No, he'll play.
ダメですよ 彼は出します
Don't make me tell you something as obvious as do not underestimate your opponent.
油断禁物なんて当たり前のこと
言わせないでください
それに 第２クオーターからは
あの２人中心に来るでしょうから
Besides, starting in the second quarter,
they'll probably come at us with those two.
はい 間違いなく
Yes, without a doubt.
The more data you have, the more accurate it is.
（リコ）データってのは
多いほど精度が上がるものよ
日向君たち２年生は
１年分多く研究されてるわ
She's been researching the second years for a whole extra year.
However, there's considerably less information about you two.
その点 ２人はまだ
情報が圧倒的に少ないし—
黒子君は 予測困難
火神君は 発展途上
Kuroko is difficult to predict
and Kagami is still developing.
桃井のウラをかける可能性が
あるとしたら あなたたちよ
If there's anyone who can
counter Momoi, it's you two.
Okay, it's up to you guys!
よし ひとまず
頼むぜ オマエら
暴れろ ルーキー！
Give them hell, rookies!
Good.
（伊月）いーぜ 思いきり行け！
Go for it!
（今吉）ん？ なっはっは
いきなりかい！
Already? It's just like Momoi said.
桃井の言うてたとおりや
（諏佐）確かに
こいつらのデータは少ない
There's relatively little data on these two.
But this didn't work in the Shutoku game!
（若松）けど これは
秀徳戦で不発だったやつだろ！
Besides, how dare a kid who just graduated from middle school...
つーか ついこの前まで
中坊だったガキが…
dunk all over the place!
（若松）バカバカ ダンクすんな
ボケェ！
Two blockers!
（観客１）ブロック２人！
（若松）なっ！ オイ コラ！？
テメー いつまでそこに…
Hey, what?
How long are you going to stay up there?
This jump... The real thing is ridiculous!
このジャンプ…
実物は マジふざけてやがる！
We can't stop him even if we know it's coming.
（今吉）分かってても
止められへんか
Oh well.
参るわ！
All this crap about data is a pain in the ass!
（火神）データがあるだの
ねーだの—
まどろっこしーんだよ！
I'll kick it all to the curb and jump!
んなもん 全部蹴散らして
跳んでやらー！
Two in a row!
（福田）２連続！
（降旗）うおお ノッてきた火神！
Kagami's on fire!
（土田）いけるぞ！
You can do it!
（誠凛(せいりん)部員たち）
いいぞ いいぞ 火神！
Go, go, Kagami!
No, this isn't good.
（原澤）いやー よくないでしょう
You can't.
ダメですよ いくら若くても
体壊すほど ムチャしたら
Even if you're young, you shouldn't recklessly destroy your body.
（リコ）あっ！ ウソ！
You're kidding!
This is an emergency!
緊急事態だわ！
小金井君 至急アップよろしく！
Koganei, warm-up!
Seirin, member change.
（アナウンス）
誠凛 メンバーチェンジです
Kagami! Change!
（小金井）火神！ 交代！
What? Why me?
は？ ちょっ…
なんでオレなんだよ ですか！
We're just getting started.
これからってときに…
Just go back!
いーから 戻れってば！
The coach noticed.
カントク 気付いてるぞー
They're subbing him out?
（観客１）あいつ 交代？
ありえねーだろー
I don't believe it.
What is Seirin thinking?
（観客２）何考えてんだ 誠凛ー
（観客３）やっぱ ちゃんと
監督いねーとこはダメだなー
Schools without a proper coach just can't cut it!
Kagami... Could it be...?
（日向）火神… まさか…？
Your injured legs haven't fully healed yet, have they?
痛めた足… 完治してないわね？
くぅっ 大丈夫っスよ！ まだ全然…
I'm fine! I'm totally...
You're not sick and there's nothing wrong with you,
（リコ）病院でも異状なしだったし
別に 出るなとは言わないわ
so I won't tell you not to play.
I'm going to tape your legs. Take off your shoes.
とにかく テーピングするわよ
バッシュ脱いで！
Damn it! Just when we were getting started...
（火神）くっそぉ…
これからってときに！
（日向）えぃっ てえぃ！
Damn it, my body moved!
（日向）やべ！ 体流れた！
Rebound!
（選手）リバン！
They're fast! Touou's countering!
（観客）うお 速(はえ)ぇ！
桐皇のカウンターだ！
（伊月）まずい…
７番190センチ ６番193センチ
This isn't good...
No. 7 is 190 centimeters,
and No. 6 is 193 centimeters.
Without Kagami, our inside has an overwhelming disadvantage!
火神が抜けて
インサイドが 圧倒的に不利だ！
リバウンドが取れない！
We can't get the rebound!
Seirin scores around Kuroko, but the movements of the remaining four second years are all known because of Momoi.
（緑間）誠凛も 黒子を中心に
得点を重ねてはいるが—
残りの２年４人は
桃井のせいで 動きが読まれている
The hole left by Kagami is huge.
やはり 火神の抜けた穴は大きい
The gap is widening.
点差が開き始めた！
Touou
Seirin
This isn't good.
まずいっスよ
くぅっ 頼む…
もう少し こらえてくれ
Please, just hang in there.
落ち着け 火神！
もっと みんなを信じろよ
Calm down, Kagami!
Have a little more faith in everyone.
I know!
分かってる… ますよ！
We'll beat Touou with team play!
桐皇は 全員一丸で倒す！
That should do it!
（リコ）できたわ！ とりあえず
この試合はこれで問題ないはず
This should get you through this game.
You can go!
行っていいわよ！
（火神）うっし！
All right!
サンキュです！
Thanks.
（リコ）すまないわね
I'm sorry.
The truth is, I don't want to send out an injured player,
（リコ）本当は 万全でない選手を
出すなんて やりたくないけど—
but we can't win without you.
火神君がいないと勝てないわ
全員一丸のバスケって
言ったけど—
We've been calling it complete team play,
but it's actually a style someone taught me.
そもそも それは“ある人”が
教えてくれたスタイルなの
Someone?
“ある人”？
I'm not strong enough to draw out everyone's full potential,
私だけの力じゃ
まだ未完成で—
みんなの力を 引き出しきれない
あげく ケガしてる
火神君に頼る始末
so I have to rely on you, even though you're injured.
My own weakness pisses me off!
自分の無力さに腹が立つわ！
う… なんスか それ？
キャラ違うっスよ
What are you talking about? This isn't like you.
You make practice regimens, you scout,
練習メニュー作って
スカウティングして—
you give us instructions on the bench,
ベンチで指示出して
マッサージにテーピング
and even massage and tape us.
If anything, you do too much.
むしろ あれこれ仕事しすぎ
You're the coach.
カントクなんだから
ドーンと構えてくんねーと…
You've got to at least come prepared for games.
試合中ぐらいは…
つか“すまないわね”で
送り出されても—
I mean,
sending me off with an apology hardly amps me up, Ma'am.
テンション上がんねーから… です
You're a brat, you idiot.
（リコ）生意気 言ってくれるわね
バカガミが！
（アナウンス）
誠凛 メンバーチェンジです
Seirin, member change.
Go get them!
行ってこい！
Yeah!
ウッス！
That's it, show some spirit
（青峰）そうそう
張り切ってくれよ
so you can entertain me a little.
（青峰）少しでも オレを
楽しませられるようにさ
You bastard!
テメェ 青峰！
Aomine!
You're finally here?
Touou
Seirin
（今吉）やっと来たか まったく…
Hurry up and get ready so you can play!
早よ 準備して 出てくれや！
What? But you're winning.
（青峰）えー
つか 勝ってんじゃん
Touou
Seirin
There's only one minute left in the second quarter anyway.
Touou
Seirin
しかも 第２クオーター
あと１分しかねーし
Touou
Seirin
No, you have to play.
ダメです 出なさい
（火神）く…
（青峰）はあ〜 ま いーけど
Fine.
Well, then...
（青峰）じゃあ…
（さつき）ああっ
Let's go.
やろーか
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
Next Episode
Why is my lemon missing?
（今吉）なんで
オレのレモンがないねん！？
（桜井）すいません！
すいません！
Sorry, sorry!
Saying sorry won't bring my lemon back.
（今吉）すいません言われても
レモン返ってこーへんねん！
（桜井）本当に すいません！
すいません！ すいませーん！
I'm really sorry!
Sorry, sorry!
（今吉）ホンマに
悪い 思てんのか？
Are you really sorry?
（桜井）若松さん すいませーん！
（今吉）ワシや ないんかい！
Wakamatsu, I'm sorry!
You're All Ridiculous
Episode 17
You're not apologizing to me?